Syed Anas Ahmed

Chennai, India | +91 8939216589

syedanas2607@gmail.com | https://syedanas.com/

Highly motivated and experienced computer science engineer with over 2 years of experience in software development, full-stack development, and web development. Strong technical skills in multiple programming languages and experience working on nine projects and two internships. Seeking a software development related job to further improve and grow my career.

EXPERIENCE

Developer & Tutorial Creator (Intern)

Feb 2022 - Aug 2022

Blockonomics, Hyderabad (Remote)

(6 months)

- Building demonstration websites using implementations of the Blockonomics API to create developer tutorials.
- Making a video explaining the demo for YouTube tutorials.
- Writing a blog post to help developers understand how to integrate Blockonomics product's API.
- Research on new topics and creation of videos on them, such as Gap Limit / Testing.
- Technologies Used: Django, React, InShot Editor App, GIT, Postman.

Web Developer (Intern)

Nov 2020 - Feb 2022

Korangle, Shujalpur (Remote)

(1.3 years)

- Full Stack new module implementation front-end (Angular), back-end (Django) and Designing (Figma).
- Fixing of the bugs raised by the QA Tester and clients in the software.
- Research work about the new feature requirement requested by the clients.
- Web scraping school information from websites for marketing purposes and updating it in Google Sheets using an automated approach with the use of Google APIs.
- Technologies Used: Angular, Django, WordPress, AWS EC2, GIT, Selenium, Figma.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.) - Computer Science

Aug 2019 - May 2023 (Expected)

GPA: 8.9/10

SRM Valliammai Engineering College, Chennai

Jun 2018 - Apr 2019

Sitadevi Garodia Hindu Vidyalaya, Chennai

Higher Secondary - Computer Science

Percentage: 84/100

High School Jun 2016 - Apr 2017

Saraswathi Matriculation School, Chennai

Percentage: 94.8/100

AREAS OF INTEREST

Full Stack Development, Software Development, Android Development, Artificial Intelligence, Cryptocurrency, Data Science, Internet Of Things.

SKILLS

Java, Python, C, JavaScript, Angular, Django, Tomcat, AWS, MySQL, MongoDB

PROJECTS

Multiplayer Chess WebApp

2020

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Java, MySQL and AWS.

Link: https://syedanas.com:8443/

Movie Rating Website

2020

Technologies used: Angular and Django.

Link: https://github.com/SyedAnas26/Movie-Rating-Website-FrontEnd

Pollify Android App

2021

Technologies used: Java, React, Django, Figma, MySQL and AWS

Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pollify

Shop the Shop Android App

2022

Technologies used: Java , Django, Figma, MySQL

Link: https://ijcrt.org/papers/IJCRT2205804.pdf

Library Management Website

2022

Technologies used: HTML, Knockout JS, Java, Tomcat, MySQL

Link: https://syedanas.com:8443/LibMag

Cyborgs Website

2022

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Django, MySQL

Link: https://cyborgs22.com/

Bottle Classifier GUI App

2022

Technologies used: PyQT5, Pyside2, Python, Matplotlib, MongoDB

Link: https://github.com/SyedAnas26/bottle_classifier_app

Rash Driving Analyser

2022

Technologies used: IoT, Flask, AI.

Link: https://syedanas.com/ppt/rash-driving-analyser.html

OTHER LINKS



https://syedanas.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/syed-anas-ahmed-826a9b1ba/



https://github.com/SyedAnas26/